Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.06.20 15:41:12
1983年是我作为一个青少年 所经历的第一个情人节。
CHRIS ROCK: 1983 was my first Valentine's Day as a teenager.
我以前从来没有在乎过情人节。
I never really cared about Valentine's Day before,
可是，现在我无法忽略它。
but now I couldn't ignore it.
情人节，让很多人想起鲜花和巧克力。
Valentine's Day makes most people think
但是对于我，我却想起了 芝加哥的黑社会。
of flowers and candy,
but it reminded me of the gangland massacre in Chicago.
情人节快乐！！！ （玛丽莲.梦露1959年主演的电影《Some Like It Hot》）
Happy Valentine's Day.
昨天，这些玫瑰花要10美圆。
Yesterday, those roses cost $10.
现在，它们涨到110美圆。
Today, they're $110.
即使你孤单一人，你也应该找个女人，
Even when you're broke,
对她说，你爱她。
you have to find a way to tell your woman you love her.
Hey!
碰上我们算你倒霉，朋友！
即使换来一顿暴打。
You picked the wrong wall today.
Even if it means getting the crap beat out of you.
情人节，连空气里都充满了爱意。
On Valentine's Day, love was in the air.
你应该看看他们是多么亲热！
You should have seen what they did after they shot him.
情人节快乐，这是给你的。
Hey.
Hi. Happy Valentine's Day.
即使在学校里，情人节也是一件大事。
Even at school, Valentine's Day was a big deal,
看起来每个人都收到了礼物。 除了我。
and it seemed like everybody
还有时间，
was getting something except me.
我们还有机会可以收到卡片。
Still a few days to go.
言下之意是， 如果我们不是好兄弟，
We could still get a card.
我一定要抢你的女友。
That look means, "If we weren't friends,
I'd smack the hope out of you."
我的来了，我有一张情人卡。
Hey, I got one. I got a Valentine's Day card.
酷。
Cool.
连我都有卡，你的也会来的。
Hey, if I got a card,
上面写什么？
I know you will.
What's it say?
（人人都恨克里斯）
玫瑰鲜，糖果甜，
Roses are red, violets are blue, you stink like a monkey
你这只臭猴，人人嫌。
and look like one, too.
节日快乐！
Happy Valey.
空气里都是“爱”啊！（倒霉）
So much for love in the air.
我13岁的时候，没有女朋友。
CHRIS ROCK: I didn't have any luck with girls when I was 13.
但我却暗恋过许多女孩。
Mostly, I just had a bunch of crushes.
为什么只能暗恋，因为机会天天有，
They call it a crush, because chances are
可是，一旦我开口，换来的却是“心碎”。
if you open your mouth, you're gonna get crushed.
她们用各种理由拒绝我，
They could have called it, "She don't like you, stupid,"
比如“我不喜欢傻瓜。”
but "crush" is just quicker.
这让我的心碎更加彻底。
那是甜姐布朗。
That's Tangee Brown.
嗨！
Hi.
她只对我说过一句话，就是：嗨。
All she ever said to me was "hi."
但这就足够了。
That's all I needed.
从那天开始，她成了我的“大巴情人”（暗恋）。
After that, she became my Bus Crush.
叫她“大巴情人”，是因为 我经常在大巴上碰到她。
I call it a Bus Crush
because this one happened on a bus.
以前，我还有“电梯情人”。
One time I had an Elevator Crush.
为了在她面前装酷， 我差点被电梯夹掉了脑袋。
I almost lost my head trying to follow her around.
这是我的“后窗情人”。
There was my Window Crush.
从此之后，她一见我就紧张。
The laws about that were a lot more relaxed at the time.
关于我的“大巴情人”，我必须指出：
There was only one problem with my Bus Crush--
她有男朋友。
she had a boyfriend.
也许我笨，可你连脑子都没有。
Why I got to be stupid?
以后我们各走各的路，你别缠着我。
You're the one who lost your hat.
I lost it because I was trying to keep you
－你现在要甩我了？ －是的。甜姐。
from getting on the wrong bus.
Oh, so I'm dumb now?
我不会在乎你了。
Yeah, Tangee.
And you're getting on my nerves.
克莱德，把我的书还给我。
Clyde, you still got my books.
拿去。
Here.
你一个人拿回去看个够吧。
You need to read them.
这真像坐山观虎斗。
Maybe they'll teach you how to act.
This must be how the drummer felt
watching Ike and Tina fight.
谢谢。
Thank you.
想坐下来吗？
You want to sit down?
－不用，我站着就好。 －坐吧，没关系。
No, that's okay.
我喜欢站在门口。
Oh, no, it's all right. I like to stand.
多谢你。
Thanks.
此时，就算有人高价卖我一张终月票， 我也愿意买！（高兴！）
At that moment, somebody could have sold me
a lifetime bus pass.
我爱你。
我老妈最爱情人节。
My mother loved Valentine's Day, and why not?
这理所当然。
I learned early on, Valentine's Day is not a day for couples.
我早就知道，情人节不是情侣的节日，
而是女人的节日。
It's a day for women.
如果女人空着手出现在男人家门口，
If a woman shows up at a man's door empty-handed, big deal.
这没有关系。
But if a man shows up empty-handed,
如果男人空着手出现，
也许，他再也没有机会出现在这里了。
he may as well not have shown up at all.
你这个猪头！
Die, you pig!
我可不是吓唬你们。
He won't forget next year.
你好！
ROCHELLE: Hello?
朱尔在家吗？ 朱尔现在没空，
GIRL: Can I talk to Drew?
我们在吃饭。
No, Drew can't come to the phone right now.
可现在是情人节?
We're having dinner.
I'm his Valentine.
什么？
His who?
His Valentine. His only Valentine.
好了，再见。
Okay, bye.
Drew, you need to tell these fast little girls
朱尔，你必须告诉那些女孩，没事别往这里打电话， 害我们晚上不得安宁。
to stop this house all hours of the day and night.
－我告诉她们了，妈妈。 －那就再说一遍。
I told them already,
这些女孩打电话说什么“情人节……”之类的话，
Well, tell them again.
They're all calling here talking about, "Well, tell him
his Valentine called."
－把我烦死了。 －放松一点。
I don't have time for that mess.
看我们的小鬼多受欢迎啊！
Relax. Boy can't help it if he's popular.
－克里斯，到现在为止，你收了几张情人卡？ －没有。
TONYA: Chris, how many Valentine cards
为什么女孩都不喜欢你？
did you get so far?
None.
因为这不关你的事。别废话。
How come girls don't like you?
-别把气出在我头上。 -嘿嘿嘿。
Because none of your business, that's why.
Don't get mad at me.
JULIUS: Hey, hey, hey.
妈，能帮我做一张情人卡吗？
Mama, can you help me make
对，自己做。
a Valentine's Day card?
这才是我的乖女，帮老爸省钱。
JULIUS: A homemade card.
That's my little girl, saving that money.
好的，宝贝。送给谁呢？
Sure, baby.
我男友。
Who's it for?
My boyfriend.
你男友? 看看我们的女儿多受欢迎啊！？
Your what friend?
Well, the girl can't help it if she's popular.
你从哪儿找的男友？ 学校里。
Where'd you get a boyfriend?
At school.
妈妈，能帮我找个地方存放情人卡吗？
DREW: Hey, Ma, do you have
a place where I can put all my Valentine's Day cards?
你准备送很多吗？
How many you giving out, boy?
哦，不是。
Well, I'm not really giving them out.
－是太多女孩子不停地送卡给我。 －小子，好样的！
Girls just keep on giving them to me.
My man.
女孩子就应该给男孩送卡。
Are girls supposed to give boys Valentine's Day cards?
她们是给他的。
Well, they're giving them to him.
你为什么不送我一张？
What's that got to do to with me?
你交男友多久了？
How long have you had a boyfriend?
就一周。
Just for a week.
－罗笑！你管管她。 －朱立业斯！别多事。
Rochelle?
Julius.
我也收到了一张情人卡， 可上面写的却是：
I wish somebody would give me
“我恨你”
a Valentine's Day card that says something besides "I hate you."
如果你想要，你可以从我这里拿一张。
Well, if you want,
我再衰，也不能接受“二手礼物”。
you can have one of mine.
And I thought getting his hand-me-downs was bad.
不用了。谢谢你。
Mm, no, thank you.
那张“我恨你”卡，是谁给你的。
Who gave you a card that said "I hate you"?
Oh, I don't know.
哦，我不知道。
It's just a stupid joke.
只是个愚蠢的玩笑罢了。
虽然我不喜欢克鲁塞，
Even though I didn't like Caruso,
但我不认为他应该遭到我老妈的“诅咒”。
I didn't think he deserved to be cursed out by my mother.
虽然老爸不浪漫，
Even though my father wasn't romantic,
但他也不笨。
he wasn't stupid, either.
他有个鞋盒，里面装满了问候卡。
He had a shoebox full of greeting cards in the house.
这足够他在任何场合应付我老妈。
He could give my mother a card for any occasion.
结婚周年快乐！
Happy Anniversary.
哦，你让我感到惊喜！
Aw, you shouldn't have.
国旗日快乐！
Happy Flag Day.
哦，你让我感到惊喜！
Oh, you shouldn't have.
光明节(犹太人一纪念节日)快乐！
Happy Chanukah.
哦，你让我感到惊喜！
Oh, you shouldn't have.
他曾经在这个盒子里藏了糖果。
He used to keep candy under the bed, too,
可惜被老鼠啃光了。
but the mice kept eating it.
.嘿，宝贝。 .
Hey, babe.
这是给你的。
Hey, baby.
This is for you.
Baby, it's not even Valentine's Day yet.
宝贝，现在还没有到情人节呢。
我知道。但这是一份特别的祝福。
I know, but... every day is special with you.
Oh, Julius, you didn't have to.
你真让我感到惊喜！
说你爱我。
But since you did...
你看现在发生了什么？
You see all this right here? You see that?
看到了吧。
That's why Tonya don't need to be running around here
想想我们的塔尼亚，
她居然也有男友了！
talking about she got a boyfriend.
朱立业斯，她才刚刚 10 岁呢。
Julius, she's ten years old.
那只是她们班上的小男生，没什么大不了的。
He's just a boy in her class.
想想那些电视新闻，
It's not big deal.
那些女孩10岁就有小孩了。
Rochelle, do you watch the news?
而且，20岁就有孙子了。
Girls are having babies at ten.
朱立业斯，你不用担心她。
And grandbabies at 20.
Drew is the one you need to be worried about.
为什么？
What for?
做父母，就要对小孩加强管教。
So a few girls like him.
There's nothing wrong with that.
朱尔才11岁，
He's 11.
他只比塔尼亚大一岁。
He's only one year older than Tonya.
你却用双重标准对待他们。
What is the difference?
她是个女孩。
She is a girl.
宝贝，你不可能处处防范，面面俱到。
Baby, you cannot protect Tonya from everything.
要打赌吗？
You wanna bet?
好好看着。
Watch me.
我就要处处防范！
I'll protect her from everything.
严防死堵！
Everything.
这很明显，老爸早就部署了作战计划。
It was clear that my father already had a plan.
爸爸这是朗诺，我的未婚夫。 （十年后。）
Daddy, this is Ronald.
先生，很高兴见到你。
My fianc?
Nice to meet you, sir.
妈妈， 老爸又把我的未婚夫打飞了。
Mama! Daddy shot my fianc?again.
爱谁谁！ 这就是完美的爱女保护计划。
Hey, say what you want, but that's effective birth control.
嘿，为什么女孩喜欢那些对她不好的坏男孩？
Hey, why do girls like guys that are mean to them?
好好男生已经落伍了。
Nice guys finish last.
也许是坏男生捉弄好男生，
Maybe the mean guys beat the crap out of the nice guys
女孩子看见了很开心。
so when the girls show up no one else is around.
你对她说了什么？
Did you say anything to her?
我帮她把书捡起来，还让位子给她坐。
I picked up her books and I offered her a seat.
哦，大哥，你真是情圣！
Oh, man, this is major.
－她叫什么名字。 －甜姐。
What's her name? Tangee.
格莱格，这是给你的。
Greg, this is for you.
请等我走了之后再打开，
Please don't open it until I leave.
－好吗？ －没问题。
Promise? Okay.
终于有情人卡了。
Valentine's Day card?
上面写着“做我的男友吧”
It says "Be mine."
爽耶！
Okay.
瞧瞧！
Yeah.
这个情人节真酷！
Man, "Be my Valentine," that's so cool.
哦，你又来了一张。
Hey, look, you got one, too.
玫瑰鲜，糖果甜，
"Roses are red, violets are blue...
人人恨你一千年！
cupid hates your guts, and I do, too."
噢！至少这次比上次更压韵。
Well, at this time he wrote a poem.
每次和甜姐在大巴上邂逅的时候，
I never knew when I'd see Tangee on the bus,
我都会心潮澎湃。
so I was always excited when I saw her get on.
－让我走。 －不。
Let me go! No.
不幸的是，她每次也同样是“心潮澎湃”的。
Unfortunately, she was always excited, too.
不是快乐的“心潮澎湃”，
Not happy excited,
而是愤怒的“心潮澎湃”。
more like "hold me back" excited.
看看你这个混球…………
Look what you did to my jacket.
我说过，我不想在巴士上碰到你…………
It's all stretched out.
You got on the bus like I told you, it wouldn't have happened.
你又不是我老爸，我为什么要听你的？
You ain't my daddy.
I don't have to do what you say.
你有种就再推我一下！！
Push me again and see what happens.
Hey. Leave her alone.
－嘿！别烦她了。 －什么？
What?
别装聋作哑，
You heard him.
你现在想怎样？
What you gonna do now?
嘿！就不用你来煽风点火了。
Hey, I don't need any help getting my ass whupped.
那是我最拿手的一件事。
That's the one thing I'm good at.
* Everybody ha-ates Chris *
别多管闲事。
???
现在是进退两难啊!
CHRIS ROCK: I couldn't back down now.
只能硬着头皮顶上去了。
I was scared if I moved I might pee myself.
不！
No.
小鬼，从我的大巴上滚下去。
Get the hell off my bus, boy.
－好的。 －不是说你。
Okay.
你，快滚。
Not you. You.
为什么要我滚？是他挑头的。
Come on, let's go.
Why I got to get off?
别瞎说。根本就不是他。
He started it.
Quit lying. He ain't start nothing.
－你就不能闭嘴吗？ －要我再说一遍？快滚！
Why don't you quit lying?
I said get off.
滚！
Now move.
你想坐下吗？
You want to sit down?
好吧。
Sure.
为什么帮我？
Why'd you do that?
不知道。我没有考虑那么多。
I don't know. I wasn't thinking, I guess.
我老爸说，你应该要帮助女生。
My father said you're not supposed to hit a girl.
－你相信你老爸说的话？ －是啊。
You know your father?
Yeah.
从没有人为我挺身而出。
Nobody's ever looked out for me like that before.
－你叫什么？ －克里斯。
What's your name? Chris.
我叫甜姐。
I'm Tangee.
给你。
Here.
一张情人卡？
A Valentine's Day card?
是啊。
TANGEE: Yeah.
刚才那个混蛋让我觉得恶心。
I was going to give it to Clyde, but he makes me sick.
谢谢。
Thanks.
真棒！我的第一个情人节。
This was great, my first Valentine's.
虽然我两手空空，什么也没送给她，
So what if it was meant for a future wife beater?
但她没有向电视里那样痛扁我。
He ain't beat me.
朱尔在家吗？
Hi. Is Drew home?
你知道现在已经超过八点半了吗？
Do you realize it's 8:30 at night?
朱尔已经睡觉了。
Drew is in bed.
他才11岁。
He is 11.
他 才 十 一 岁 ！
E-L-E-V-E-N. 11.
11岁
I... Go home.
回家吧。
If I see you around my child again,
如果我看到你接近我的孩子，
I'm calling the cops.
懂了吗？
You got that? Yeah, I-I...
………… 不用解释，我明白。
Okay, I know, I know, girl, I know.
又灭掉一个。
Beat it.
这是我最喜欢的。
Ooh, these are my favorites.
Mmm! Mm-mm-mm.
－再见爸爸。 －再见儿子。
DREW: All right, bye, Dad.
See you later, son.
你好久没有来我们学校了。
Daddy, you haven't walked us to school in a long time.
我知道，是很久了。
I know. It's been a while.
你今天不是休息吗？
Aren't you supposed to be sleeping?
我过一会就休息。
Yeah. I can get my rest later.
妈妈说你最不喜欢学校。
Mama said you don't like walking us to school.
她瞎说。
That's not true.
想要几毛钱吗？
You want a dollar?
All right.
.给你。
There you go.
既然我在这里，
Hey, since I'm here,
不如你指给我看，谁是你的男友？
why don't you show me which one of these kids
is your boyfriend.
Oh, um... there he is.
就是他。杰克！
James!
代我向他问好。
So that's him, huh?
Yeah.
All right.
－再见，爸爸。 －再见，宝贝。
Bye, Daddy.
All right, bye, baby.
我要和你谈谈。
Can I talk to you for a minute?
－和我？
Who, me?
过来。
Yeah, you.
你叫什么名字？
Get over here.
我的名字叫“你管不着”
What's your name?
My name is "Don't worry about what my name is."
你以为你是大众情人？
What, you think you're some kind
我不知道你是什么意思？
of ladies' man or something?
连这也不懂？
I don't know any ladies.
……不……不懂。
They're not even No. Uh, I don't know...ou?
－你是谁？ －别管我是谁。
Who are you?
Don't worry about who I am.
你今天甭想收到什么情人卡了。
Worry about who you're giving them cards to.
－我要我妈妈 －你是妈妈的乖宝宝？
I want my mama.
So you a mama's boy?
－是啊。
Yes.
听着，乖宝宝，离我女儿远点儿，
Well, listen up, mama's boy.
听见了吗！
You stay away from my daughter, you hear me?
Huh?
嘿，不许哭！
Hey, man, stop that.
不许哭！
MAN: Hey, stay away from that boy!
－离那个孩子远点。 －我只是和他聊聊天。
Get out of here!
JULIUS: I was just talking to him.
他不愿意和你聊天。
MAN: Hey, you, I'm talking to you!
老爸今天去了塔尼亚的学校，
CHRIS ROCK: While my father was getting rid of Tonya's valentine,
我真希望他能来这里。
I wish he'd been around to get rid of mine.
糖果鲜，玫瑰秀，
"Roses are red, violets are blue...
带你老妈回非洲！
"Please go back to Africa
"and take your mother with you.
情人节快乐！
Happy Valentine's Day."
如果再收到这样的卡， 我真想立马去非洲。
CHRIS ROCK: Another card like this, and I might just go to Africa.
你又躲在墙旁边？
What's wrong with you?
我只是想避开卓依。
I'm trying not to bump into Joy again.
学校就这么大，躲也没用。
The school's only but so big.
You're bound to run into her sometimes.
我太紧张了，最好别碰见她。
I just don't want to blow it.
我不知道下一步怎么办？
I don't know what my next move is.
－你没有送卡给她？ －没有。
Well, did you get her a card?
那就送一张吧。
No. Then that's your next move.
你可以和我一起来。
You can come with me.
－我也准备送一张卡。 －给谁的？
I was going to go get one anyway.
巴士上的女孩。她昨天给我一张。
For who?
The girl on the bus.
还没听你说过啊？
She gave me one yesterday.
虽然我收到情人卡比你早一步，
And you didn't tell me?
可你小子有大事也不能瞒着我啊。
I know I go to bed early, but you could still call
and wake me up when something this important happens.
我现在就准备告诉你的。
Yeah, well, I wanted to tell you in person.
－我在他男朋友动粗之前，英雄救美…… －你英雄救美？
I broke up a fight between her and her boyfriend.
是啊，她就给我了一张卡。
You broke up a fight?
Yeah, and she gave me this card.
帅哥，这绝对是惊天地，泣鬼神！
Dude, this is huge.
这么伟大？我不知道。
Is it? I-I don't know.
我只是得到了一张卡。
It... it's just a card.
这卡的意思是：我属于你，来吧！
A card is, "I'm yours for the taking."
在你收到卡之前，你是怎么做的？
How in there do you have to be before you get it?
甜姐送卡给我的时候，
Why is it that when it comes to me,
我有点不知所措。你知道的，
you know so much about girls,
当别人送卡给你的时候，你总会有点紧张的。
but you freak out when one gives you a card?
我猜着第一次都会紧张的。
I guess it's kind of like not being able
to cut your own hair.
在你给女孩送礼物之前，
CHRIS ROCK: Before you ever buy a girl a gift,
你应该送她一张完美的卡片。
the first thing you've got to do is buy her the perfect card.
这过火了。
Nah, that's too much.
你们都没有亲过呢。
You haven't even kissed her yet.
你有吗？
Have you?
那，这个呢?
Um...
how about this one?
（我的女王）
"You know the deal.
你知道的，我想你做我的情人。
I want you to be my valentine."
这个很酷，但更适合普通男女。
That's cool, but it's more for a friend than a girl.
噢，这张好！
Whoa, cool.
相对而言，我希望你做我的情人。
"Relatively speaking,
would you be my valentine?"
这才是最好的。
This is perfect.
给甜姐？不了，不合适。
For Tangee? No thanks.
不，是给卓伊的。
No, for Joy.
格莱格总是有好人缘。
CHRIS ROCK: Greg never fought being a nerd.
这让我想不通。
I always wondered how that worked out for him.
快点，甜心！
Come on, honey!
－格莱格，什么时候换了车？ －同事借给我的。
Greg, when did you get this car?
Well, the Bentley's in the shop.
我更喜欢这张。
I kind of like this one.
（做我的情人！）
大哥，这卡太贵了
Dude, this card is $2.50.
嘿，这个时候可不能小气。
Hey, you've got to pay to play, right?
快，把卡拿来。
Quick, give me my card.
给你。
Here.
－送给你的。 －谢谢！
This is for you.
别，别，别。
Thank you.
－回家再看。 －好。
No, no, no, no.
Read it when you get home.
Okay.
啊，刚才真紧张。
Man, that was close.
噢。
What's this?
哈哈，我收够了。
Oh, ha, ha, very funny.
克里斯、
Chris!
为什么要这样？
How could you?
我看到克努斯戏弄你，
When I found out how Caruso had been teasing you,
我本来想给一张真的贺卡来安慰你的。
I thought you'd appreciate a real valentine from someone.
看来，我多事了。
Obviously, I was wrong.
如今，老师们才不会给你的孩子送卡。
CHRIS ROCK: Nowadays, you wish all the teacher gave your kids
我不知道你是送给我的。
were cards.
I didn't know it was yours.
我在学校里越来越不受欢迎，
While I couldn't have been less popular, back at home,
可在家里，朱尔却越来越吃香。
Drew couldn't have been more popular.
你好。
Hello?
告诉朱尔，情人节快乐！
GIRL: Hey, is my valentine home yet?
不，朱尔还没有回家。
No, Drew is still outside playing.
别再往这里打电话了。
Stop calling here!
什么？什么？
What's wrong, what's wrong?
这些电话让我心绪不宁。
All these girls calling.
It's getting on my nerves.
已经有很多人要约他，
I already have enough to deal with.
你能想象学校门口有多少女孩接他放学吗？
Can you believe
there's some maniac at the school
看来，我必须去亲自接他。
threatening the kids?
I've got to go pick them up from school today.
至少，朱尔在学校里可以保护塔尼亚。
Well, at least Drew's there to protect Tonya.
我们应该怎样处理这个问题？
Now, what are we going to do about Drew and these girls?
（装聋作哑）
Huh?
每过五分钟就有人来，不是打电话就是敲门，
What?
Julius, every five minutes,
some girl is calling or knocking at the door.
朱尔这么小就招峰引蝶……
Drew is way too young to get this much attention.
这没什么大不了的。
Rochelle, it's nothing, okay?
朱尔已经11岁了。
Drew's only 11 years old.
再说，你也管不了那些女孩。
He don't care nothing about those girls.
现在，有的男孩在12岁就当爸爸了。
Boys are becoming fathers even at age 12.
在43岁当外祖父。
CHRIS ROCK: And great-grandfathers at 43.
放松点。
Baby, relax.
别担心。
Don't worry about it.
你是不操心。
You don't worry about it,
可我不想这么早当奶奶。
'cause I ain't about to let nobody call me Grandmama.
因为老妈抱着这种想法，
CHRIS ROCK: With my mother on the job,
所以，我在33岁才有女朋友。
I didn't get a girl till I was 33.
这个时候，朱尔刚刚结束聚会。
Meanwhile, Drew had more girls than an Usher after-party.
－情人节快乐！朱。 －谢谢，米雪儿。
Happy Valentine's Day, Drew.
Oh, thank you, Miss Johnson.
虽然在学校很不爽，
CHRIS ROCK: As bad as my Valentine's Day had been going, I knew
但一想起我的“巴士情人”，烦恼就一扫而空。
I could count on my bus crush to make it all right.
嘿，克里斯，我给你占了座位。
Hey, Chris, I saved you a seat.
多谢。
Thanks.
能问你个问题吗？
Can I ask you something?
你为什么总和那个讨厌鬼在一起？
What?
How come you go with a guy that you always fight with?
我和他结束了。
I'm not going with him anymore.
他是个猪头。
He's stupid.
我可以放心了。
CHRIS ROCK: That's all I needed to hear.
嘿，送你一个礼物。
Hey, I got you something.
哦，你真好。
Really? That's so sweet.
东西呢？
What else?
什么东西？
What else, what?
你不是要送我礼物？
Where's the gift?
我只是想送你一张卡。
I only got you a card.
就这个？
That's it?
今天是情人节啊！！！
It's Valentine's Day,
你就这么小气，只给我一张破卡？
and all you got me was this cheap-ass card?
我们才刚认识啊。
I-I-I just met you.
那，鲜花呢？
So? Where's the flowers?
糖果呢？
Where's the candy?
我还以为我们很有缘分， 我还以为你很重视我。
I thought I meant something to you.
早知道我还不如待在学校里，
I thought we had a connection.
You know, I could have stayed
with Clyde's sorry ass
以后再也不理睬你。
if this is how you were going to treat me.
－能不能小声点？ －你还叫我小声点，
Can you please quiet down?
你为什么不小声点。
You don't tell me to be quiet.
Why don't you be quiet?
不如直接说，闭嘴！
Better yet, shut up!
要我小声点，
Tell me to be quiet.
你又不是我老爸。
You ain't my daddy!
这个倒霉的情人节让我哭笑不得……
CHRIS ROCK: Getting cursed out on a bus
is not really how I expected to end my Valentine's Day,
但这证实了我的观点。
but it did prove my point.
越“倾心”，越“伤心”。
If you have a crush, you get crushed.
This is nothing but a piece of paper!
真希望司机能把我赶下车。
I don't need this!
CHRIS ROCK: Now, where was the bus driver
with a bat when you needed him?
……
And I'd kiss your little funky cheek,
but I could have stayed with Clyde.
把你这张不值钱的废纸拿走，我不需要……
Here, take back your stupid card.
朱尔，你必须把这张卡退给蔷森女士。
Drew, you got to return these cards to Miss Johnson.
30岁，还结过婚，居然送卡给我们11岁的孩子。
A 30-year-old married woman
giving cards to my 11-year-old son.
那这些糖果怎么办？
What about the candy?
我们还是写一张卡回去拒绝她。
I think sending
the cards back makes the point.
虽然甜姐不要我的卡，
CHRIS ROCK: Giving the card to Tangee didn't work out,
－但我老妈肯定很高兴能收到卡。 －谢谢，宝贝。
but I knew my mother would appreciate one.
Thank you, sweetie.
你没必要送我卡。
You didn't have to give me a card.
我知道你爱我。
I already know that you love me.
这个卓伊是什么东西？
Who the hell is Joy?
卓伊？
Joy, are you dating a black guy?
你和一个黑人约会了？？？
是的，但发生在五年后。
CHRIS ROCK: She did, five years later.
* Everybody hates Chris! *